Welcome to our wrong item sent product compliance training.
A wrong item sent product condition issue occurs when a customer receives a product they consider
different from the one they ordered.
Customers may think that the product they received is not the one that they ordered when it doesn't
match the expected color, pattern, size, quantity or material described on the relevant product
detail page.
Doesn't match the specific country, version or model described on the product detail page or it's
a totally different product than was ordered.
Let's meet Lee.
Lee was excited to find a brand ABC shirt in blue in the Amazon store.
She'd been looking for this particular shirt in blue for her son's birthday, but hadn't been able
to find it anywhere.
Lee ordered the shirt with excitement and any company shipped the order.
When Lee opened the package, she found that the shirt that had been delivered was red.
Lee was disappointed, returned the shirt and complained to Amazon.
Any company sent the wrong item and is not complying with Amazon's seller code of conduct, product
authenticity and quality guidelines and condition guidelines.
If you receive a notification from Amazon related to a wrong item sent, you should determine the
root cause of the issue to prevent future customer complaints.
Mateo sells multiple products in the Amazon store.
He monitors what his customers say about his products by signing in to seller central and regularly
reviewing buyer messages using the buyer seller messaging service.
Customer feedback, product reviews, A to Z claims, returns, the customer complaint summary and the
voice of the customer dashboard.
Here are some tips to prevent sending the wrong item to a customer.
Tip number one, describe your products clearly and upload accurate images to the product's detail
page so that customers know what to expect.
Tip number two, regularly carry out internal checks and audits to review quality control processes.
Tip number three, inspect your products to ensure they function correctly and match their descriptions
on the detail pages.
Tip number four, work with trustworthy suppliers to ensure you list quality products.
Tip number five, train your staff to verify that your products contain all the correct parts and
are placed in the correct packaging and ensure they send the correct version of a product for a
specific order.
Tip number six, check that all products are labeled correctly and validate your product's variations.
Tip number seven, carry out an audit of your inventory if you receive a wrong item sent notification
to check that the remaining inventory doesn't have the same issue.
And tip number eight, label and store returned products separately to avoid confusion.
Ensure that issues with returned products aren't passed on to other customers.
To find help pages with information on preventing these issues,
go to Seller Central and type preventing product condition issues, product authenticity and quality
and condition guidelines in the search field at the top of the page.
It's important to note that non-compliance with Amazon's policies may affect your ability to sell
in the Amazon store.
Remember to keep your account health from being affected by wrong item sent violations.
Always ensure that customers receive the product as it's described on the product detail page.
This concludes our wrong item sent product compliance training.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.